A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Vice Presidential records, Secretariat, Weekly Briefing Notes, Series 14 FA261
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller Vice Presidential records, Secretariat, Weekly Briefing Notes, Series 14
1975 May-1977 January
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
U.S. Bureau of the Census
FA261
3.76 Cubic Feet 8 legal-sized document boxes
Biographical / Historical
President Gerald R. Ford nominated Nelson A. Rockefeller to fill the vacant vice presidency following the resignation of President Richard M. Nixon in August 1974. Rockefeller served as Vice President from December 19, 1974, to January 20, 1977.
File Plan
Former Classification: III 26 14
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Primarily chronological
Scope and Contents
The Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development series consists of statistics generated each week for President Gerald Ford and Vice President Nelson Rockefeller by the U.S. Bureau of the Census and Statistical Policy Division of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) from May 1975 to January 1977. Vincent P. Barabba was Director of the Bureau of the Census and Joseph W. Duncan was Deputy Associate Director of the Statistical Policy Division for the OMB. In September 1976, Robert L. Hagan became Acting Director of the Bureau of the Census.
These statistical reports are organized into the following sections: Section A: General Economic Indicators, Section B: General Social Indicators and Socioeconomic Series, Section C: Government Activity, and Section D: Environment, Science, and Culture. (In Box 1, Section C is Health, Education, and Welfare and Section D is Government Activity.) Section E: Selected Subjects appears occasionally throughout the series with statistics on specific topics. The statistics that appear in each report are highlighted in yellow through the table of contents. The reports include multicolored graphics with brief summaries.
Most folders contain a weekly chartbook detailing the frequency of each section of statistical data along with its appearance in the weekly briefing notes through the entire year. For example, Section A, National Income and Product, Gross National Product is followed by the dates it appears in the briefing notes.
Some folders starting in Box 2 contain a short memo from Vice President Rockefeller to President Ford about the highlights in each weekly briefing notes report. Richard Allison, a member of the Vice President's staff, wrote the memos found at the end of Box 3.
Briefing notes organized by subject (special reports), such as healthcare, housing, crime and criminal justice, appear at the end of the series in Box 8.
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Construction and Housing, Money and Credit, Leading Indicators, Special Reports: Characteristics of America Youth: 1974
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Topics covered: Production and Trade, Prices, Money and Credit, Population Statistics, and Welfare
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Construction and Housing, Energy, Raw Material, and Commodities, Money and Credit
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 May 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earning, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Government
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Topic covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Agriculture, Leading Indicators, Family Statistics, Health Statistics, Welfare, Public Safety
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction and Housing, Money and Credit
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Construction and Housing, Money and Credit, Family Statistics, Government
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Prices, Construction and Housing, Money and Credit
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Topics covered: Employment & Unemployment, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Prices, Agriculture, Leading Indicators, Health Statistics, Education Statistics, Public Safety
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Prices, Construction and Housing, Education Statistics
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Money and Credit, Indicators of Business Activity, Family Statistics, Consumer Behavior
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Production and Trade, Construction, Income, Consumption, and Wealth
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 July 28 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Indicators of Business Activity, Health, Public Safety, Government Operations, Environment
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 August 4 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemploymet, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Construction, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 August 11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Prices, Money and Credit, Section E – Selected Subjects- Persons of Spanish Origins
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 August 18 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Topics covered: Production and Trade, Construction, Money and Credit, Health, Work
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 August 25 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Prices, Construction, Science
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 September 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Housing, State and Local Employment
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 September 8 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Prices, Construction, Population, Education
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Money and Credit, Work, Social Welfare and Security
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 September 22 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Prices, Construction
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Topics covered: Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Prices, Money and Credit, Education, Public Safety
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 October 6 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Leisure and Recreation
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 October 14 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Money and Credit, Section E – Selected Subjects- Selected Social and Economic Characteristics of the Metropolitan and Nonmetropolitan Population: 1974 and 1970
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 October 20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Topics covered: Production and Trade, Construction, Health, Income, Consumption, and Wealth, Housing
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 October 28 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Money and Credit, Population
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 November 3 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Energy, Raw Materials, and Commodities, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Housing, Social Welfare and Security
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 November 10 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Prices, Construction, Money and Credit, Education
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 November 17 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Construction, Population, Health
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 November 24 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Income, Consumption, and Wealth, Public Safety
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Energy, Raw Material, and Commodities, Agriculture, Leading Indicators, Transportation
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Prices, Construction, Population, Education
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1975 December 15 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Construction, Money and Credit, Health
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 January 5 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Prices, Construction, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Housing, Public Safety
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 January 12 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Prices, Population, Health
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 January 19 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Construction, The Family, Selected Characteristics, Section E – Selected Subjects - Shareownership of Public Corporation, Driver Licenses
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 January 26 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction, Equal Opportunity, Government Operation
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 February 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Construction, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Population, Income, Consumption, and Wealth
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 February 9 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Construction, Transportation
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 February 16 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction, Money and Credit, Social Welfare and Security
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 February 23 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction, Education
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 March 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Public Safety, Section E- Selected Subjects- Trends in Employment of College and University Graduates in Business and Industry
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 March 8 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Prices, Construction, The Family, Public Safety
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 March 15 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Construction, Money and Credit, Population, The Family, Health, Education
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 March 22 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 March 29 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Topics covered: Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance Payments, Health, Section E - Selected Subjects- Motor Vehicle Facts
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 April 5 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Prices, Construction, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 April 12 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Construction, Money and Credit, Health, Income, Consumption, and Wealth, Housing, Public Safety
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 April 19 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Production and Trade, Construction, Money and Credit, Income, Consumption, and Wealth
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 April 26 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Transportation, Housing, Social Welfare and Security, Science
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 May 3 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Section E – Selected Subjects- Characteristics of Women
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 May 10 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Prices, Construction, Public Safety, Science
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 May 17 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Construction, Money and Credit, Elections
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 May 24 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Prices, Science
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 June 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payment, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Health, Work, Income, Consumption, and Wealth, Environment
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 June 8 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction, Education
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 June 15 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Construction, Section E – Selected Subjects- Demographic Characteristics of Aging
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 June 21 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Construction, Public Safety
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 June 28 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Health, Education
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 July 5 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Construction, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 July 12 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Housing
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 July 19 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Construction, Money and Credit, Transportation, Education, Culture, Section E – Selected Subjects- Language Usage
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 July 26 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 August 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments,Indicators of Business Activity, Population
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 August 9 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Construction, Agriculture, Health, Social Welfare and Security
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 August 16 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction, Money and Credit, The Family
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 August 23 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 August 30 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Indicators of Business Activity, Leisure and Recreation
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 September 6 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 September 13 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Money and Credit
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 September 20 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Production and Trade, Construction, Transportation, Leisure and Recreation
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 September 27 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Topics covered: Production and Trade, Prices, Population, The Family, Health
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 October 4 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Construction, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Population, Income, Consumption, and Wealth
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 October 12 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction, Money and Credit, Environment
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 October 18 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Construction, Education
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 October 26 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 November 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Work, Government Operations
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 November 8 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Prices, Construction, Money and Credit, Population, Income, Consumption, and Wealth, Government Operations
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 November 15 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Production and Trade, Construction, Energy, Raw Material, and Commodities, Health, Education, Leisure and Recreation, Government Operations
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 November 22 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 November 29 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Topics covered: Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Prices, Population, Health, Work, Social Welfare and Security, Public Opinion, Science
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 December 6 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Prices, Construction, Agriculture, Indicators of Business Activity, Selection E – Selected Subjects- U.S. Military and Economic Assistance
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 December 13 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Employment and Unemployment, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Construction, Money and Credit, The Family, Public Safety
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1976 December 20 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Topics covered: National Income and Product, Production and Trade, Construction, Public Safety, Selection E – Selected Subjects- Spanish Origin Population
- Weekly Briefing Notes on U.S. Domestic Development, 1977 January 4 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Topics covered: Employment and Unemployment, Hours, Earnings, and Productivity, Production and Trade, Foreign Trade and Balance of Payments, Prices, Indicators of Business Activity, National Defense
- Briefing Notes: National Income and GNP Account, 1975 May 5 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Topics covered: Index of Components of National Income
- Briefing Notes: Raw Materials, 1975 May 15 (Box 8, Folder 3)